Inventory of the Hamid Shawkat collection, 1952-2001
Hoover Institution Archives
- Other Revolutionary Groups' Issuances, 1961-2001 (Box 15-28)
  - Etehād-i kumunīst-hā-yi īrān (United Communists of Iran), 1976-1979 (Box 16)
    - Other publications of the United Communists of Iran, booklets and pamphlets, 1978 (Folder 16: 11)
  - Hizb-i dīmukratīk-i mardom-i irān (Democratic Party of the People of Iran), 1987 (Box 16)
    - Official publications from congress meetings, booklets, 1987 (Folder 16: 12)
    - Ghodrat 'arfī yā ghodrat shar'ī, book, undated (Folder 16: 13)
  - Hizb-i dīmukrat kurdīstān īrān (The Democratic Party of Kurdistan Iran), 1981-1987 (Box 17)
    - News bulletins, pamphlets, March 1985-February 1987 (Folder 17: 1)
    - Reports from the 5th congress of the Democratic Party of Kurdistan, booklets, 1981-1982 (Folder 17: 2)
    - Summary of Irān shahr, pamphlet, 1982 (Folder 17: 3)
    - Memoranda, 1981 (Folder 17: 4)
  - Hizb-i millat-i īrān (Party of the Nation of Iran), 1977-1978 (Box 17)
    - Newsletters, 1977-1978 (Folder 17: 5)
  - Hizb-i kumunīst-i īrān (Communist Party of Iran), 1972-1984 (Box 17)
    - Reports from congress meetings, booklets and newsletters, 1983 (Folder 17: 6)
    - News pamphlets, 1983-1984 (Folder 17: 7)
    - Dars-hā az inqilāb-i chīn ,(Lessons from the Chinese Revolution), booklet, undated (Folder 17: 8)
    - Awsul-i kumunīsm va takāmil-i susīālīsm az takhīl beh a'lām, Friedrich Engels, booklet, 1972 (Folder 17: 9)
    - Daw bīneshadr hizb-i kumunīst-i īrān, book, 1983 (Folder 17: 10)
    - Bi-su-yi āyandeh, news organ of the young followers of the Communist Party of Iran, no. 5, May 1978 (Folder 17: 11)
    - Tarīkh-i mokhtasar-i hizb-i zahmatkeshān-i vīetnām, booklet, 1973 (Folder 17: 12)
  - Hizb-i tudah (Tudeh Party), 1966-1989 (Box 17-18)
    - Tudeh, central organ, pamphlets, 1968-1971 (Folder 17: 13)
    - Tudeh, newsletters, 1966 (Folder 17: 14)
    - Khatrat az tarikh-i hizb-i tudeh, Ehsan Tabari, article, undated (Folder 17: 15)
    - Chap ravī: bīmārī-ye kudakāneh dar kumunīsm, V.I. Lenin, booklet, 1972 (Folder 17: 16)
    - Political pamphlets, 1969-1986 (Folder 18: 1-2)
    - Leaflet supporting Democratic Tudeh Party, undated (Folder 18: 3)
    - Miscellaneous bulletins, 1966-1977 (Folder 18: 4)
    - Mardom, newspapers and newsletters, 1969-1984 (Folder 18: 5-6)
      Organ of the Tudeh Party.
    - Māh va kunfidirasīyun, report, 1973 (Folder 18: 7)
    - Namāneh az zabāneh khodeshun, report, undated (Folder 18: 8)
    - Navīd, newsletter, 1978 (Folder 18: 9)
    - Open letter to Maryam Kīānourī (member of the Tudeh Party) from Ahmad Lankarani, Paris, 1983 (Folder 18: 10)
    - Rāh erānī, journal and newsletter, 1988-1989 (Folder 18: 11)
    - Afriqā rezmandeh, pamphlet, 1973 (Folder 18: 12)
    - Nagrashī bar mobārzat-i tudeh-i akhīr, report, 1977 (Folder 18: 13)
    - Donyā (The Universe), journals, 1974 (Folder 19: 1)
      Magazine was originally started by Dr. Taghī Erānī to promote democratization of Iranian society. After his arrest by Rezā Shāh Pahlavi, the remaining founders of the magazine relaunched the Tudeh Party movement.
    - Donyā, nos. 1-2, and 4, journals, 1975 (Folder 19: 2)
    - Donyā, nos. 1-4, 8-10, journals, 1976 (Folder 19: 3)
    - Donyā, nos. 1-2, 4, 7-10, and 12, journals, 1977 (Folder 19: 4)
    - Donyā, nos. 2-5, and 8, journals, 1978 (Folder 19: 5)
  - Jamā'yi dafā az hequq-i bashār dar īrān (The League for the Defense of Human Rights in Iran), 1984-2001 (Box 20)
    - Newsletters, 1984-1989 (Folder 20: 1)
    - Bulletins, 1985-1987 (Folder 20: 2)
    - Norouz (New Year's) card with greeting, 1984 (Folder 20: 3)
    - Pamphlets on the rights of prisoners, 1984-1987 (Folder 20: 4)
    - Liga Report, nos. 5-6, newsletters and pamphlets, December 1988-May 1989 (Folder 20: 5)
    - Hequq-i bashār, no. 48, journal, September 2001 (Folder 20: 6)
  - Jame'yat-i dafā az āzādi va hakomeyat-i millat-i īrān (Society for the Defense of Freedom and Liberty for the People of Iran), 1986-1987 (Box 20)
    - Pamphlets, 1986-1987 (Folder 20: 7)
    - Newsletters, 1986 (Folder 20: 8)
  - Jame'yat-i inqilābi-yi zanān-i āfghānīstān (Revolutionary Association of the Women of Afghanistan), news bulletin, 7 March, 1993 (Box 20)
  - Jameh-yi fārekh āltasselan-i āzādī khān-i īrānī moqīm āllemān federāl va berlan gharbī, 1980-1982 (Box 20)
    - Constitution, pamphlet, 1981-1982 (Folder 20: 10)
    - Central publication, pamphlets and booklets, 1980-1981 (Folder 20: 11)
      Folder contains 6 issues.
    - Newsletters and announcements, 1981 (Folder 20: 12)
  - Jameh-ye mu'alamān-i īrān (Iran Teachers' Association), 1985-1989 (Box 20)
    - Bulletins, 1985-1989 (Folder 20: 13)
    - A New Path from Dictatorship to Democracy in Iran, booklet, July 1988 (Folder 20: 14)
  - Jameh-ye susīāl dimukrat-hāyeh īrān (Social Democratic Association of Iran), bulletins, 1988 (Box 20: 15)
  - Jameh-ye susīālīst-hāyeh īrānī dar urupā (Association of Iranian Socialists in Europe), 1965-1968 (Box 20)
    - Susīālīsm, newsletters, 1967-1968 (Folder 20: 16)
    - Susīālīsm, nos.5 and 7, booklets, November 1965-October 1966 (Folder 20: 17)
    - Matn-i klāsīk-i mārksīsm, pamphlet, undated (Folder 20: 18)
  - Jebhe mīllī īrān (National Front of Iran), 1963-1986 (Box 20-21)
    - Irān āzād, newsletters, June 1963-December 1965 (Folder 20: 19-22)
    - Irān āzād, newspapers, September 1966-November 1986 (Folder 21: 1-5)
    - Booklet from Irān āzād, undated (Folder 21: 6)
    - Khabar nāmeh, newsletters, 1972-1978 (Folder 21: 7)
    - Khabar nāmeh, booklets, 1976-1977 (Folder 21: 8)
    - Khabar nāmeh, booklets, 1978 (Folder 21: 9)
    - Bakhtār emruz, newspaper, 1971-February 1975 (Folder 21: 10)
    - Bulletins, 1976-1977 (Folder 21: 11)
    - Bulletins, from European chapter, 1987 (Folder 21: 12)
    - Rāhī bi-su-yi āyandeh: che bāyad kard?, report, 1964 (Folder 21: 13)
    - A Collection of Mosaddeq's Speeches, booklet, 1964 (Folder 21: 14)
    - Kuchek khān, poem by Ja'afar Kush Abādi, booklet, 1971 (Folder 21: 15)
    - Parah'ī az asnād-e Savak(Documents on Iranian Secret Police, SAVAK), booklet, 1971 (Folder 21: 16)
      Edition published by the National Front of Iran.
  - Jebhe mīllī dimukratīk īrān (National Democratic Front of Iran), 1978-1980 (Box 22)
    - Azādī, nos. 3, 21-27, 29, 32,and 36,newspapers, 1978-1979 (Folder 22: 1)
    - Manifesto for Democracy and National Reconstruction, pamphlet, 1979 (Folder 22: 2)
    - Newsletters, reports, and flyer, 1977-1980 (Folder 22: 3)
  - Jebhe mosaddeqī-yi īran (Mosaddeq Front of Iran), journals, 1980 (Box 22: 4)
    Includes issue nos. 1-2 and 5-6 of Jomhouri
  - Jomhureh khavāhān mīllī īrān (National Republicans of Iran), 1984-1989 (Box 22)
    - Constitutions, 1988 (Folder 22: 5)
    - Bulletins, 1986-1988 (Folder 22: 6)
    - Pamphlets, 1985-1990 (Folder 22: 7)
    - Newsletters, 1988-1989 (Folder 22: 8)
    - Reports, 1989 (Folder 22: 9)
    - Notes and newsletters, 1984-1988 (Folder 22: 10)
    - Letter from Doctor Hossein Javādi to Hamīd Shawkat regarding National Republicans of Iran, 9 October, 1985 (Folder 22: 11)
  - Jomhurī islāmī (Islamic Republic), 1979-1991 (Box 22)
    - Newsletters, 1979-1981 (Folder 22: 12)
    - Announcement by Abolhasan Banīsadr to the People of Iran, newsletter, 1981 (Folder 22: 13)
    - Nāmeh-hāyeh beh sefārat-i jomhurī islāmi, pamphlet, 1991 (Folder 22: 14)
    - Inqilāb-i islāmī va mārksīsm, pamphlet, undated (Folder 22: 15)
      Stamp on cover reads "Islamische Studentenunion (ISU) Universitat des Saarlandes."
    - Irān dar āyneh-yeh ā'mar, book, 1981 (Folder 22: 16)
  - Junbish-i āzādī baksh-i mīllī-yi īrān (Committee for Independence for the Nation of Iran), newspaper, 1971 (Box 22)
    Includes issue of Nabarde
  - Jonbesh-i dimukratīk inqillābī zahmatkishān (The Democratic Revolutionary Movement of Iranian Toilers), 1973-1983 (Box 22)
    - Bulletins, 1983 (Folder 22: 18)
    - Asnādī az junbish-i inqilābī, booklets, 1973-1981 (Folder 22: 19)
  - Kānun-i nivīsandagān-i īrān "dar tasid" (Association of Iranian Writers "in Exile"), 1980-1989 (Box 22)
    - Circulated bulletins, 1980-1989 (Folder 22: 20)
    - Khabar nāmeh, nos. 1-2, February-May 1989 (Folder 22: 21)
  - Komīteh barāyeh dafā hequq-i bashār va pīshbardān dar īrān (Council for the Defense of Human Rights for Prisoners in Iran), 1978 (Box 23)
    - Central publication, nos. 12-14, journals, 1978 (Folder 23: 1)
    - Central publication, no. 15, journal, 1978 (Folder 23: 2)
    - Central publication, journals, 1978 (Folder 23: 3)
  - Imām khomeini, 1975-1980 (Box 23)
    - Circulated bulletins to the people of Iran, 1975-1978 (Folder 23: 4)
    - Circulated bulletins to Iranian students in Europe, 1978-1980 (Folder 23: 5)
    - Notes, September 1978 (Folder 23: 6)
      In Persian and German.
    - Summary of interview with Khomeini in Le Monde newspaper, France, June 1978 (Folder 23: 7)
  - Komalah, Sāzemān-i kordīstān hezb-i kumunīst īrān (Organization of the Communist Party of Kurdistan Iran), 1979-1986 (Folder 23)
    - News bulletins, pamphlets, 1984-1986 (Folder 23: 8)
    - Newsletters from students at Kurdish universities, 1980 (Folder 23: 9)
    - Newsletters from Komalah chapters overseas, 1986 (Folder 23: 10)
    - Komalah agenda, defined by proceedings of 3rd congress, pamphlets, 1982 (Folder 23: 11)
    - Khabar nāmeh-yeh kurdīstān, nos. 5-6, newsletters, 1979 (Folder 23: 12)
  - Miscellaneous revolutionary groups' issuances, 1971-2001 (Folder 24)
    - Articles and reports, 1977-1979 (Folder 24: 1)
    - Leaflets, 1971-1978 (Folder 24: 2)
    - Papers, 1971-1988 (Folder 24: 3-5)
    - Printed materials, 1977-2001 (Folder 24: 6)
  - Nahzat-i āzādī-yi īrān (The Freedom Movement of Iran), 1978-1986 (Box 24)
    - Bulletins, 1978 (Folder 24: 7)
    - Nāmeh sar goshādeh beh rahbar-i inqilāb, article, 1988 (Folder 24: 8)
    - Nāmeh sar goshādeh az Mohandas Bazargān, 1985 (Folder 24: 9)
    - Pamphlets, 1974-1986 (Folder 24: 10)
    - Peyām imām khomeinī, newsletters, 1978 (Folder 24: 11)
  - Sāzemān-i kārgarān inqilābī-yi īrān (Organization of Revolutionary Workers of Iran), 1983 (Folder 25)
    - Peyām kārgar, nos. 2-4, pamphlets, 1983 (Folder 25: 1)
    - Peyām sorkh, nos. 7-8, pamphlets, 1983 (Folder 25: 2)
    - Rāh-i kārgar, no. 1, booklet, 1983 (Folder 25: 3)
    - Rigā-ī kārgar, nos. 2-4, pamphlets, 1983 (Folder 25: 4)
    - Shurā, nos. 1-2, pamphlets, 1983 (Folder 25: 5)
  - Sāzmān-i inqilābi-yān-i kumunīst, booklets, 1975-1976 (Box 25: 6)
    Includes booklets on guerrilla policy
  - Sāzemān-i javanān va dānishjuyān-i dimukratīk īrān (Organization of Democratic Youth and Students of Iran, ODYSI), newsletter, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Sāzmān-i chirīk'hā-yi fadā'ī-i khalq-i īrān (Organization of the People's Scarifice Guerrillas of Iran), 1971-1980 (Box 25-26)
    - Central organ, 1977 (Folder 25: 8)
    - Newsletters and bulletins, 1975-1977 (Folder 25: 9)
    - Newsletters and bulletins, 1978-1979 (Folder 25: 10)
    - Booklets and leaflets on workers, 1975 (Folder 25: 11)
    - Yādnāmeh-yeh sho hadā-yi sīyākal, article, 1971 (Folder 25: 12)
    - Open letter from Ayatollāh Khomeinī to People's Fedai'ī Guerrillas, 1978 (Folder 25: 13)
    - Reports and other writings, 1978 (Folder 25: 14)
    - The Development of Capitalism in Russia, V.I. Lenin, book, 1976 (Folder 25: 15)
      Translated into Persian by the People's Fedai'ī Guerrillas.
    - Shānzdahomeh āzar dāw-bāreh tekrār shāwd, article, undated (Folder 26: 1)
    - Books published by the People's Fedāi'ī Guerrillas of Irān, 1973-1977 (Folder 26: 2-3)
    - 'Asr-i 'āmal, nos. 1-2, and 7, booklets, undated (Folder 26: 4)
  - Sāzmān-i etehād-i mobārzeh dar rāh ījād-i hizb-i tabaqeh-yi kārgar (Organization of Fighters for the Creation of a Working Class Party), books and pamphlets, 1973-1980 (Box 26)
    - Central organ, nos. 1-2, books, 1973-1978 (Folder 26: 5-6)
    - Central organ, nos. 3-4, books, 1977-1978 (Folder 26: 7)
    - Political pamphlets, 1974-1980 (Folder 27: 1)
    - Constitution, booklet, undated (Folder 27: 2)
    - Parcham-i andīsheh-yi māu tseh dun, book, October 1976 (Folder 27: 3)
  - Sāzemān-i mārksīst-lenīnīst-i toufān (The Party of Labour of Iran), 1964-1987 (Box 27)
    - Toufān, newsletters, 1964-1970 (Folder 27: 4)
      Organ of the Party of Labour.
    - Toufān, newsletters, 1971-1977 (Folder 27: 5)
    - Toufān, booklet, 1966 (Folder 27: 6)
    - Political booklets and pamphlets, 1973-1977 (Folder 27: 7)
    - Leaflets, 1969 (Folder 27: 8)
    - Chīn bad az māu, booklet, 1975 (Folder 27: 9)
    - Inqilāb, no. 9, newsletter, undated (Folder 27: 10)
    - Beh pīsh, no. 3, newsletter, September 1974 (Folder 27: 11)
    - Parcham-i sorkh, nos. 1-2, journals, 1971 (Folder 27: 12)
    - Setāreh sorkh, newspapers and newsletters, 1973-1978 (Folder 27: 13)
  - Sāzemān-i mujāhidīn-i khalq-i īrān (Organization of the People's Mujahidin of Iran), 1974-1987 (Box 27-28)
    - Peyām mujāhid, newsletters, 1974-1975 (Folder 27: 14)
    - Political pamphlets, 1977 (Folder 27: 15)
    - Nāmeh sar goshādeh beh hāy'at-i dabīrān kunfidirāsīyun-i jahānī, booklet, undated (Folder 27: 16)
    - Book of writings from MEK, 1979 (Folder 27: 17)
    - Mujāhidīn-i khalq cheh kar mī konād?, report, 1983 (Folder 27: 18)
    - Peykār-i khalq, newsletters, 1977 (Folder 27: 19)
    - Treaties and manifestos, 1971-November 1975 (Folder 28: 1)
    - Student publication, nos. 78-79 and 88, journals, 1987 (Folder 28: 2)
    - Newsletters and bulletins, 1972-1982 (Folder 28: 3-4)
    - Open letter from MEK to Dr. Manuchehr Hezarkhani, West Germany, 1988 (Folder 28: 5)
    - Miscellaneous articles, 1981-1983 (Folder 28: 6)
  - Sāzmān-i peykār dar rāh-i āzādī-ye tabaqeh kārgar (Peykar), 1977-1982 (Box 28)
    - Newsletters and bulletins, 1977-1978 (Folder 28: 7)
    - Poster with title: "Asrat-i āzādī asrat-i khalq hast,", undated (Folder 28: 8)
    - Report, 1979 (Folder 28: 9)
    - Avvaleh ordibehesht, booklets and newsletters, 1981-1982 (Folder 28: 10)
      Journal of student supporters of Peykār.
  - Sāzmān-i susīālīst-hāyeh īrān (Organization of Iranian Socialists), 1971-1989 (Box 28)
    - Bulletins, 1989 (Folder 28: 11)
    - Junbish-i susīālīstī, nos. 4 and 10, booklets, 1985-September 1986 (Folder 28: 12)
    - Booklets, 1971-1983 (Folder 28: 13)
  - Sāzmān-i vāhedat-i kumunīstī, pamphlet, 1979 (Box 28)
    - Rāhā'ī, no. 4, pamphlet, 1979 (Folder 28: 14)
  - Shorā-yā motāhed-i chap barāyeh dimukrāsī vā istiqal (Left United Council for Democracy and Independence), 1979-1986 (Box 28)
    - Informational pamphlets, 1981-1982 (Folder 28: 15)
    - Pamphlet on the work of the Tudeh Party, 1979 (Folder 28: 16)
    - Dimukrasī va valayat-i faghī, booklet, 1982 (Folder 28: 17)
    - Newsletters, 1981-1986 (Folder 28: 18)
    - Writings on democratic left in Iran, newsletters, 1979-1986 (Folder 28: 19)
    - Peyām āzādī, no. 24, newsletter, 1983 (Folder 28: 20)
- Printed Materials, 1957-1991 (Box 29-35)
  Books, booklets, and pamphlets on political and social theory, human rights, Iranian identity, guerrilla fighters in Vietnam and Cuba, and general world history appear in the Printed Materials series. A number of the Communist and Marxist-themed works in this series were published by Mazdak publishing house in Florence, Italy. Translations and summaries of works by Karl Marx and V.I. Lenin are also prevalent in this series and complement the many reproductions of these works that were published and distributed by various revolutionary organizations as propaganda.
  - 2 enteghād beh chirīk'hā-yi fadā'ī khalq, M. Shu'a'iyān (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), booklet, 1975 (Folder 29: 1)
  - 5 nāmeh-ye sar goshādeh beh sāzemān-e charīkhā-ye fedā'ī khalq-e irān, M. Shu'a'iyān (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), booklet, 1975 (Folder 29: 2)
  - 19 bahman tī'urik, nos. 3-4, booklets, April-July 1975 (Folder 29: 3)
  - Ab-yāh-sarāb?, Behrouz Amdadī Asal, booklet, 1993 (Folder 29: 4)
  - Afsāneh khalq-hāyi īrān,(Myth of Iranian Nationalities), M. Makan (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), 1969 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Alefbeh-hāyeh mobārzeh, booklet, undated (Folder 29: 6)
  - Andīsheh va inqi lāb, nos. 7, 9-10, (Etehād barāyeh āzādi-kār), journals, 1984 (Folder 29: 7-9)
  - Akhlāghiat va zībā-i shenāsī shernishevsky, A.V. Lunacharsky (Bābaki), book, 1957 (Folder 29: 10)
  - Ashgar-i inqilāb, Lahouti (Florence: Mazdak Publshing House), book, undated (Folder 29: 11)
  - Asnād-i tārikhī: jonbesh-e kārgarī, susīāl dimukrasī, va kumunistī īrān, vol. 7, (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), book, 1975 (Folder 29: 12)
  - Avāyeh vahsh-yā-mā kholīyā'i mahtarī, 1989 (Folder 29: 13)
  - Az bahrān-i ightesādī tā inqillāb-e ijtemā'ī, M. Mossart, booklet, 1979 (Folder 29: 14)
  - Az kojā shuru konīm? Ahmad Ghotbī, book, 1978 (Folder 29: 15)
    Also by the Campaign for the Restoration of Trade Union Rights in Iran.
  - Az dāw sāl, book, 1980 (Folder 30: 1)
    Does not include pages 1-10.
  - Barāyeh chap-i dīgar, C. Vassīgh, journals, 1991-1995 (Folder 30: 2)
    Folder contains 2 issues, published in France.
  - Bar dīgar bā sharīātī, nos. 1, 3-9, pamphlets, undated (Folder 30: 3)
  - Barnāmeh 'amal (nehzāt islāmī), no. 7, journal, 1977 (Folder 30: 4)
  - Basij, nos. 1-2, journals, 1979 (Folder 30: 5)
  - Bi-su-yi āzādī, nos. 2-4, journals, 1978 (Folder 30: 6)
  - Bīst-āw chehār sā'at dar khāb va bīdārī, Samad Behrangī, booklet, 1969 (Folder 30: 7)
  - Bolshevīsm va estālīnīsm, Leon Trotsky (Marxist Publishing House), pamphlets, August 1970 (Folder 30: 8)
  - Chekīdeh marksīsm, K. Korsch (Ahangi), book, undated (Folder 30: 9)
  - Chand shehr az pahneh-ye nabarde, M. Shu'a'iyan (Florence:Mazdak Publishing House), booklet, 1975 (Folder 30: 10)
  - Dafā'ī, Dr. T. Erānī, book, 1972 (Folder 30: 11)
  - Darbāreh a'mal diktāturī hameh jānbeh bar burzhvāzi,(Intisharat Bahram Arām), booklet, 1978 (Folder 30: 12)
  - Davā bar ghodrat, Hossein Malaki, book, 1978 (Folder 30: 13)
  - Dimukrasī mostaghīm va shurāhā, Dr. Karīm Ghassīm (Maziar), booklet, 1979 (Folder 30: 14)
  - Del az rastam āyad beh khasham, Mustafa Rahimi, booklet, 1973 (Folder 30: 15)
  - Der kleine schwarze fisch, Samad Behrangi, booklet, 197? (Folder 30: 16)
    Book originally written in Persian then translated into German.
  - Daw majaleh az: hizb-i kumunīst-i a'rāq, (Intisharat-i Esma'el Sharifzādeh), pamphlet, 1978 (Folder 30: 17)
  - Empīrīyālīsm va garāyesh-ha-i dar ān,(Tehran: Shabahangi), book, 1979 (Folder 30: 18)
  - Enqilāb-i fālestīne, no. 15, (Florence:Mazdak Publshing House), journal, July 1970 (Folder 30: 19)
  - Etehād-e-hāyeh kārgarī, V.I. Lenin, (Nabarde kārgar), book, undated (Folder 30: 20)
  - Gozāreshī dar bāreh-yeh nabesamāneh-hāyeh keshāvarzī mamlekat, Hossein Malaki, book, 1978 (Folder 30: 21)
  - Gozāresh sīyāsī kumiteh markazī beh kungreh chehārom-i hizb-i kumunīst vīetnām, Le Duan, book, 1978 (Folder 31: 1)
  - Ho shī mīn, (Florence:Mazdak Publishing House), 1970 (Folder 31: 2)
  - Hekāyateh noruz, Parī Sekandarī, 1991 (Folder 31: 3)
  - Haquqī dar bāreh vāgheyeh siyākal, journal, undated (Folder 31: 4)
  - Inprecor, no. 10, journal, 17 October, 1974 (Folder 31: 5)
  - International Affairs: selected articles from the Review of the Communist and Worker Parties for Theory and Information, nos. 2-3, 1-4 and 6, 1971-1973 (Folder 31: 6)
  - Iran Rouge 1 and Iran Red 2 journals, circa1973 (Folder 31: 7)
  - Jang sāzish, M. Shu'a'iyān (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), booklet, 1976 (Folder 31: 8)
  - Junbish-i zanān va masā'il-i hijāb, journal, undated (Folder 31: 9)
  - Kārnamāh Mosaddeq, (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), booklet, 1974? (Folder 31: 10)
  - Kishvar sāzemān-hāyeh kumunistī khalq-hāyeh khāvar zamīn, V.I. Lenin (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), undated (Folder 31: 11)
  - Khabar nāmeh dākhili rejīme, booklet, 1989 (Folder 31: 12)
  - Khālef jarīyān, daftar duvvum, book, 1976 (Folder 31: 13)
  - Khāterat-i jang-hāyeh roha'i baksh-i kuba, Che Guevara (Amuzāsh Part), book, 1969 (Folder 31: 14)
  - Khāterat-i man az Lenīn: Lenīn dar bāreh masā'il-i zanān, Clara Zetkin, pamphlet, undated (Folder 31: 15)
  - Kumīteh kārgaran, T. Murphy (Nabarde kārgar), book, undated (Folder 31: 16)
  - Kunferānse Hassan Nazih beh menasbat yād būd Mosaddeq, pamphlet, 5 March 1981 (Folder 31: 17)
  - Mabāni a'lam iqtisād, Niki Tin, booklet, undated (Folder 31: 18)
  - Manifest: masā'il-i inqilāb va susīālism, nos. 1-2, journals, 1974 (Folder 31: 19)
  - Manifest: masā'il-i inqilāb va susīālīsm, nos. 5-6, journals, 1975 (Folder 32: 1)
  - Matīrīyālīsm dīyālīktīkī, T. Arānī (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), booklet, undated (Folder 32: 2)
  - Moghadam-i eghtesād-i sīyāsī,(Florence) Mazdak Publishing House), booklet, 1969 (Folder 32: 3)
  - Moshkallat va masā'il-i junbish, book, 1977 (Folder 32: 4)
  - Marksīsm, no. 1, journal, 1968 (Folder 32: 5)
  - Mīllī shodan san'at naft dar sar-ā-sar-i īrān, Ahmad Rana'si, book, 1984 (Folder 32: 6)
  - Monasbat tabaqat va-hezāb, Marx, Engels, and Lenin, booklet, 1959 (Folder 32: 7)
    Includes a collection of essays.
  - Mosaddeq va malakī, Cosroe Chaqueri, pamphlet, 1986 (Folder 32: 8)
  - Naksh-i isrāyel va rezhīm pahlavī dar khāvar mīyāneh, M. Shu'a'iyān (Florence:Mazdak Publishing House), booklet, 1977 (Folder 32: 9)
  - Nāmeh, Haj Said Javādī Alī Ashgar, book, 1976 (Folder 32: 10)
  - Neghād bar barnāmeh-yi gotā,(Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), book, 1970 (Folder 32: 11)
  - Neghāhi beh ru'ābat shurui va nahzat-i inqilābī jangal, M. Shu'a'iyān (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), book, 1968 (Folder 32: 12)
  - On the Asiatic Mode of Production, booklet, 1979 (Folder 32: 13)
  - Padafrāh-i namakī, Nehmat Azarm, booklet, 1985 (Folder 33: 1)
  - Pāsukhi beh dāshnāmeh-ye malakīyun, booklet, undated (Folder 33: 2)
  - Pāsukh-hāyeh nasanjīdeh beh qādāme-hāyeh sanjīdeh, M. Shi'a'iyan (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), book, 1976 (Folder 33: 3)
  - Pedar, mādar, mā motehamīn, Ali Shariāti, book, 1972 (Folder 33: 4)
  - Persian Journal for Science and Society, nos. 2, 3 and 35, journals, 1983-1984 (Folder 33: 5)
  - Peyām āshnā, journal of the Women's Committee of the Association of Iranians in Quebec, September 1987 (Folder 33: 6)
  - Peyām beh khalq-hāyeh jahān, Che Guevara (Amuzashi Part), book, 1969 (Folder 33: 7)
  - Rāh samād, no. 1, pamphlet, 1977 (Folder 33: 8)
  - A Reply to the Collaborators of the Reactionary Regime of Khomeini,, Cosroe Chaqueri, pamphlet, August 1980 (Folder 33: 9)
  - Ruhanīyāt, susīyālīsm va barnāmeh-ye māh, Rosa Luxembourg (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), pamphlet, undated (Folder 33: 10)
  - Rushe-hāyeh polīce dar vīetnām,(Hannover: 12 Mahram Publishing), book, 1977 (Folder 33: 11)
  - Sendīkālīsm dar jahān: jonbesh-i sendīkāl'i dar keshvar-hāyeh jahān sevom, Farhang Ghassemi (trans.) (Paris: Boniad Mosaddeq), book, 1964 (Folder 33: 12)
  - Shīshomin nāmeh sar goshādeh beh charīk-hāyeh fedā'ī, M. Shu'a'iyān (Florence:Mazdak Publishing House), booklet, December 1976 (Folder 33: 13)
  - Shi'i-garī: behkunand va rahvarī konand, Ahmad Kosroui, book, undated (Folder 33: 14)
  - Taghdī bar khetrat-i Nourredīn Kīyānourī, nos. 1-2, Bābak Amir Khosroui, 1972-1974 (Folder 34: 1)
  - Tarīkh-i hezb-i kumunīst (bolshvīkī), Verlag 20 Mai Publishers, book, 1972 (Folder 34: 2)
  - Tarīkh-i sīh sāl-i īrān, Bijān Jazānī, book, undated (Folder 34: 3)
  - Tulu-i enfejār yā peyām va peyāmbar, Hāj Said Javādi Ali Ashgar, book, September 1977 (Folder 34: 4)
  - Vāhedat mīllī, nos. 1-2, journals, 1974 (Folder 34: 5)
  - Vazāyef-i farhangī tabaqeh kārgar, A. Lunacharsky, (Communist Publishing House), booklet, 197? (Folder 34: 6)
  - V.I. Lenīn dar bāreh mārksīsm, (Florence: Mazdak Publishing House), booklet, undated (Folder 34: 7)